Guide to the William R. and Louise Fielder Sheet Music Collection
Department of Special Collections
- Series 13. Famous People, 19th Century
  - Jenny Lind's greeting to America New York: Firth, Pond & Co.,1850.New York: S. C. Jollie ,1850 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    Composed by Julius Benedict
    Written by Bayard Taylor, Esq.
    Lithographer: N. Sarony, New York
  - Sally come up Boston: Russell & Patee,1862 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    Arranged by Frederick Buckley
    Lithographer: L. Prang & Co., Boston
    Performed by Dave Reed and Buckley's Serenaders
  - Horace Greeley's funeral march Philadelphia: Lee & Walker,1862.Philadelphia: W. H. Boner & Co. ,1862 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    Music by Pierre Latour
    Also published by Oliver Ditson, Boston.
  - Annie Laurie New York: William Hall & Son,n.d. (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Within a mile of Edinburg town: Scotch ballad Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co.,n.d.Boston: C. C. Clapp & Co. ,n.d. (Box 24, Folder 2)
    Lithographer: Crap & McCarthy
    Performed by Madame Sontag and Catherine Hayes
    Also published by T. S. Berry, New York and D. A. Truax, Cincinnati.
  - The grand North eastern boundary march, respectfully inscribed to His excellency Governor Fairfield, Governor of the State of Maine New York: Firth & Hall,1839 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    Composed by Charles M. King
  - Gov. Cleveland's grand march, to His Excellency Grover Cleveland New York: C. H. Ditson & Co.,1882.Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co. ,1882 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    Also published by Ludden & Bates, Savannah; Otto Sutro, Baltimore; Geo. D. Newhall & co., Cincinnati; J. E. Ditson & Co., Philadelphia; Lyon & Healy, Chicago; and J. L. Peters, St. Louis.
  - Fremont's grand republican march, arranged from two popular airs Boston: Nathan Richardson,1856 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    Arranged by Nathan Richardson
  - Happy Bayadere (Je suis la Bayadère): the admired French chansonnette, with French and English words Philadelphia: J. E. Gould,1849.Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co. ,1849 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    Composed by N. C. Boscha
    Lithographer: McClees & Germon, Philadelphia
    Also published by T. S. Berry, New York.
  - Home sweet home Cincinnati: W. C. Peters & Sons,1871.Louisville: Peters, Webb & Co. ,1871 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    Performed by Mrs Wood at the concert of the Musical Fund Society in Philadelphia
    From :Selections of Scotch Songs as sung by Jenny Lind
    Also published by Holbrook & Long, Cleveland and Balmer & Weber, St. Louis.
  - How sleep the brave: to the memory of the illustrious patriot Abraham Lincoln St. Louis: Endres & Compton,1865.Philadelphia: Louis Meyer ,1865 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    Music by Carlo Bardetti
    Words by William Collins
    Also published by John Church, Jr., Cincinnati.
  - Anna Bishop's march, founded on Bellini's celebrated rondo finale from La Sonnambula and introducing the new brilliant variations Charleston: George Oates,1849.Philadelphia: E. L. Walker ,1849 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    Arranged by N. C. Bochsa
    Lithographer: Nagel & Weingaertner, New York
    Also published by Dubois & Warriner, Pond, Firth & Co., Wm. Vanderbeck, New York; S. W. March & Co., Boston; and George A. Oates & Co., Augusta.
  - Within a mile of Edinburg town: Scotch ballad Cincinnati: W. C. Peters & Sons,1871.Louisville: Peters, Webb & Co. ,1871 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Fair beauteous queen: a favorite song & trio [New York]: [Thomas Birch],1839 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    Written and composed by William Clifton
    Lithographer: C. E. Lewis; N. Currier's Lith.
  - Hamlet galop, homage to Edwin Booth New York: S. T. Gordon,1869 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    Music by Da Costa
    Lithographer: Gurney; Bufford Bros., New York
  - Funeral march, performed at the obsequies of the Hon. Daniel Webster Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co.,1852.New York: Gould & Berry ,1852 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    Music by Beethoven
    Lithographer: Bufford's Lith., Boston
    Also published by G. W. Brainard & Co., Louisville and C. C. Clapp & Co., Boston.
  - Fairy bride polka, as performed at the levee's of General Tom Thumb and Lady, Comd. Nutt and Miss Minnie Warren New York: Firth Son & Co.,1864 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    Composed by G. R. Cromwell
    Lithographer: Major & Knapp, New York
  - We live Ômid the bounding with variations on 'Chi naeque al rimbombo' and 'Salut à la France' New York: Firth, Pond & Co.,n.d. (Box 24, Folder 5)
    From :New Editions of Jenny Lind's songs
  - Nelly Gordon: song Boston: Geo. P. Reed & Co.,1854.Providence: E. W. Billings ,1854 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    Music by Joseph P. Webster
    Written by Sidney Dyer
    Lithographer: L. H. Bradford & Cos., Lith.
    Also published by Brabant & Co., Chicago and George Dutton, Jr., Rochester.
  - I come! I come!, an admired song composed and dedicated to Her Majesty Queen Victoria New York: Atwill,1833 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    Composed by J. Z. Hesser
    Lithographer: G. W. Lewis, New York
  - Rose Atherton [two copies] New York and Philadelphia: E. Ferrett & Co.,[1845] (Box 24, Folder 5)
    Written by Charles Jefferys
    Lithographer: A. Newsam; P. S. Duval, Lith., Philadelphia
  - Rose Atherton: a ballad Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co.,n.d. (Box 24, Folder 6)
    Written and composed by Charles Jefferys
    Lithographer: Sharp, Peirce & Co., Lith.
  - La naranjera: the orange girl [Philadelphia]: Marietta Gazzaniga,1858 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    Composed by Maestro Schochdopole
  - I pity and forgive, the last words of General Simon Bolivar New York: Firth & Hall,1831 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    Poetry by S. Woodworth, Esq.
    Performed by Mr. Jones
  - Pirates' chorus quick step New York: Horace Waters,1849.New York: William Hall & Son ,1849 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    Music by Allen Dodworth
    Performed by Dodworth's Cornet Band
    From :The Enchantress
  - The Swedish melodies: correct American edition New York: William Vanderbeek,1850 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    Written and composed by Henry Cimber
    Lithographer: Sarony, New York
  - Rest, spirit, rest: grand requiem march to the memory of Abraham Lincoln New York: William A. Pond & Co.,1865.Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co. ,1865 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    Music by E. Hoffman
    Also published by C. Y. Fonda, Cincinnati; Root & Cady, Chicago; and H. N. Hempstead, Milwaukee.
  - Boz in Boston: a quick step as performed in the Melo Drama of the Naide Queen, composed and arranged for the piano forte Boston: Henry Prentiss,1842 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    Composed and Arranged by J. Friedheim
    Enclosure: Program for 'Romantic Mr Dickens' by H. H. and Marguerite Harper, performed at the Plymouth Theatre, Boston, November, 1940, with ticket. Lithograph of 'Dickens as he appeared in his first appearance in America, from the Madice portrait.'
  - Kane's funeral march, composed and respectfully inscribed to the memory of Elisha Kent Kane, M.D., U.S.N. Philadelphia: Lee & Walker,1859 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    Composed by J. C. Beckel
    Arranged by William H. Shuster
  - La Pasadita: a Mexican National air Philadelphia: A. Fiot,1850 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    Music by Bochsa
    Lithographer: P. S. Duval, Philadelphia
    Performed by Anna Bishop
  - Napoleon's farewell Boston: G. P. Reed & Co.,1854 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    Music by F. James
    Words by Lord Byron
  - Napoleon's grave New York: William Hall & Son,n.d. (Box 24, Folder 8)
    Music by S. Nelson
    Poetry by W. Ball, Esq.
    Performed by Mr Parry, Jr.
  - Hildebrandt Montrose: swell song New York: C. H. Ditson & Co.,1875.Philadelphia: Lee & Walker ,1875 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    Written and composed by Edward Harrigan
    From :New Songs of Miss Jennie Hughes
    Also published by John Church, Jr., Cincinnati; O. Ditson & Co., Boston; J. C. Haynes & Co., Boston; and Lyon & Healy, Chicago.
  - Jenny Lind's song Farewell my fatherland Philadelphia: Lee & Walker,[1850].Pittsburgh: H. Kleber ,[1850] (Box 24, Folder 8)
    Lithographer: F. S. Duval, Steam Lith. Press, Philadelphia
    Also published by Wm. T. Mayo, New Orleans.
  - Bonaparte crossing the Rhine Boston: C. H. Keith,n.d. (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - General Tom Thumb's grand wedding march, dedicated to General Tom Thumb and his lady Philadelphia: Lee & Walker,1863 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    Lithographer: T. Sinclair's, Lith., Philadelphia
  - Ossian's serenade Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co.,1850.New York: J. E. Gould & co. ,1850 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    Music by Ossian E. Dodge
    Also published by G. W. Brainard & Co., Louisville; S. Brainard, Cleveland; H. D. Hewitt, New Orleans; and C. C. Clapp & Co., Boston.
  - The big sun flower: song Cincinnati: John Church, Jr.,1868.New York: C. H. Ditson & Co. ,1868 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    Music by Billy Emerson
    Lithographer: Strobridge & Co., Cincinnati
    From :Billy Emerson's Songs and Dances
    Also published by O. Ditson & Co., Boston; C. W. A. Trumpler, Philadelphia; Root & Cady, Chicago; and Balmer & Weber, St. Louis. Enclosure 'Love, Poker and a separation,' Millie's column, by Millie Robbins, April 6, 1971
  - The big sun flower: song Cincinnati: John Church, Jr.,1867 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    Lithographer: Ehrgott, Forbriger & Co., Lithographer, Cincinnati
  - On yonder rock reclining New York: Endicott,n.d.New York: Jollie & Millett ,n.d. (Box 24, Folder 9)
    Composed by D. F. E. Auber
    Performed by Mrs. Austin and Mr. Sinclair
    From :Auber's grand opera 'Fra Diavolo'
  - Mother kissed me in my dream New York: William A. Pond & Co.,1864.Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co. ,1864 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    Also published by J. H. Hidley, Albany; Lee & Walker, Philadelphia; Root & Cady, Chicago; and H. N. Hempsted, Milwaukee.
  - Norma's song (Where are now the hopes I cherished) Boston: Russell & Tolman,n.d.New York: Horace Waters ,n.d. (Box 24, Folder 10)
    From :Songs & Ballad sung by Miss Catharine Hayes
    Also published by Albert E. Jones, Indianapolis.
  - Seven songs as unpretentious as the Wild Rose Hollywood: The Bond Shop -Carrie Jacobs-Bond & Son,1901 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    Words and Music by Carrie Jacobs-Bond
    Shadows / words and music by Carrie Jacobs-Bond --Parting / words by William Ordway Partridge, music by Carrie Jacobs-Bond --Just a wearyin' for you: alto / words by Frank Stanton, music by Carrie Jacobs-Bond --De las' long res' / words by Paul Laurence Dunbar, music by Carrie Jacobs-Bond --I love you truly: alto / words and music by Carrie Jacobs-Bond --Still unexprest: alto / words and music by Carrie Jacobs-Bond --Des hold my hands tonight: alto / words and music by Carrie Jacobs-Bond.
    William Ordway Partridge; Carrie Jacobs-Bond; Frank Stanton; Paul Laurence Dunbar
  - Fleurs de fantasie: valse brillante Buffalo: Jewett & Mischka,1869 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    Music by Alfred H. Pease
    Lithographer: The Sage Sons & Co., Lith., Buffalo
    From :Compositions of Alfred H. Pease
  - In our green valley New York: William Hall & Son,[1853 -1857] (Box 24, Folder 10)
    Music by G. Verdi
    Words by G. Linley
    Performed by Signora Vestvali
    From :The favorite gipsy songs in Il Trovatore
  - Woodman, spare that tree!: quick step New York: Firth, Pond & Co.,1848 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    Performed by Dodworth Cornet Band
  - Folks that put on airs Philadelphia: William H. Coulston,1858.New York: Firth, Pond & Co. ,1858 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    Music by W. H. Coulston
    Words by H. Angelo
    Lithographer: Herline & Hensel, Philadelphia
    Performed by E. F. Dixley
    Also published by O. Ditson, Boston; W. C. Peters & Co., Cincinnati; and G. Willig, Baltimore.
  - Wave high the red bandanna Washington: Edward F. Droop,1888 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    Words and Music by Emma Washburn
  - Toll the bell mournfully, written and composed on the death of President Abraham Lincoln: solo Philadelphia: Lee & Walker,1865 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    Written and composed by C. Everest
  - The Taft and Sherman waltz Los Angeles: Westland Publishing Co.,1908 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    Written and composed by Virginia L. Caley
    Lithographer: Harris & Ewing
  - When Erin shall stand Ômid the Isles of the sea St. Louis: J. L. Peters & Bro.,1866.Cincinnati: A. C.Peters & Bro. ,1886 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    Music by Robert Emmet
    Lithographer: Ehrgott, Forbriger & Co., Lithog., Cincinnati
  - Gently sighs the breeze: the popular duett New York: s.d.,n.d. (Box 25, Folder 2)
    Performed by Jenny Lind and Marietta Alboni
  - Take back the ring dear Jamie: Scotch ballad New York: William Hall & Son,1858 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    Written by James Linen, Esq.
  - Lotta polka St. Louis: Balmer & Weber,1867 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    Music by Theresa Remlab
  - Nobody Philadelphia: Lee & Walker,1870.Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co. ,1870 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    Arranged by Owen Fawcett
    From :Owen Fawcett's songs
    Also published by Chas. W. Haris, New York.
  - Hildebrandt Montrose: swell song New York: C. H. Ditson & Co.,1875.Philadelphia: Lee & Walker ,1875 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - The grave of Bonaparte: song Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co.,1843.Philadelphia: J. E. Gould ,1843 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    Music by L. Heath
    Performed by Hutchinson Family
  - Ristori grand gallop Philadelphia: Lee & Walker,1867.Troy: Charles W. Harris ,1867 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    Also published by Ziegfield Gerard & Co., Chicago; C. C. Mellor & Co., Pittsburgh; J. T. Wamelink, Cleveland; A .& S. Nordheimer, Toronto; and James A. McClure, Nashville.
  - The banks of the Guadalquiver New York: Atwill,1847 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    Composed by L. Lavenu
    Lithographer: E. J. Brown, Jr.
    From :Linda di Chamounix
  - Thedesco's Spanish song La Colasa New York: Atwill,1847 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    Lithographer: F. Davignon; P. Hass
    From :Fortunate Tadesco
  - Domani! Domani, oh me felice (Ah sure, he'll never deceive me); I strive to forget thee [verso] New York: Atwill,[1845] (Box 25, Folder 3)
    Composed by Walter Maynard [verso]
    Lithographer: E. Brown, Jr.
    Performed by Madame Rosina Pico
  - When Erin shall stand Ômid the Isles of the sea St. Louis: J. L. Peters & Bro.,1866.Cincinnati: A. C.Peters & Bro. ,1886 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Bonnie Doon: a song or duet, arranged with an accompaniment for the piano forte Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co.,n.d. (Box 25, Folder 4)
    Written by Robert Burns
  - Why do I weep for thee?: ballad New York: William Hall & Son,[1848 -1858] (Box 25, Folder 4)
    Composed by W. V. Wallace
    Written by George Linley
    From :Songs and ballads sung by Miss Catharine Hayes
  - Home of my heart, or, I breathe once more my native air Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co.,[1844 -1857] (Box 25, Folder 4)
    Music by R. F. Harvey
    Words by J. W. C.
  - Why do I weep for thee?: ballad New York: William Hall & Son,[1848 -1858] (Box 25, Folder 4)
- Series 14. Fashion
  - Dolly Varden: quadrille Philadelphia: Lee & Walker,[1872 -1875].Halifax: Peiler, Sichel & Co. ,[1872 -1875] (Box 25, Folder 5)
    Composed by C. H. R. Marriott
    Lithographer: Sinclair & Son, Lith., Philadelphia
    Also published by O. Ditson, Boston and E. Peiler & Bro., St. Johns, N.B.
  - The bloomer waltz New York: Wm. Hall & Son,1851.New Orleans: H. D. Hewitt ,1851 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    Composed by William Dressler
    Lithograph 'Costume for Summer,' Lith. of Sarony & Major, New York
  - The bloomer schottisch New York: William Hall & Son,1851.New Orleans: H. D. Hewitt ,1851 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    Lithograph 'Bloomer Costume -Autumn Dress,' Lith. of Sarony & Major, New York
  - Dolly Varden galop New York: Wm. A. Pond & Co.,1872.Boston: Koppitz, Pruper & Co. ,1872 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    Composed by W[illai]m A. Pond, Jr.
    Also published by C. Y. Fonda, Cincinnati; M. Gray, San Francisco; Munger Bros., St. Paul; and H. N. Hempsted, Milwaukee.
  - Folks that put on airs Philadelphia: Lee & Walker,1863 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Just arrived from Saratoga, the Grecian bend: song Philadelphia: Lee & Walker,1868 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    Composed by David A. Warden
    Written by David A. Warden
  - On the beach at Cape May: schottische Philadelphia: R. Wittig & Co.,1868 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    Music by R. Wittig
  - Jockey hat and feather Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co.,1860.Boston: C. C. Clapp & Co. ,1860 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    Music by W. H. Brockway
    Poetry by Fred Wilson
- Series 15. Fires
  - The fireman's song: adapted to a celebrated march Boston: Parker & Ditson,1839 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    Adapted by John Smith
    Music has been folded and mailed under Buffalo post mark as a stampless cover. The rate from Buffalo to Detroit was 7 1/2 cents
  - Pity the homeless, or, burnt out Boston: White, Smith, & Perry,1871.Chicago: Root & Cady ,1871 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    Words and Music by James R. Murray
    Lithographer: Chas. H. Crosby & Co., Lithography, Boston
    Also published by S. Brainard & Sons, Cleveland; and Lee & Walker, Philadelphia.
  - On the bosom of night when the weary were sleeping, composed for and dedicated to the respective Fire Engine and Hose Companies of the City and County of Philadelphia and sung at Vauxhall by Mr. J. Turbill (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - The fireman's heart is bold and free: descriptive song and chorus, composed and respectfully dedicated to the American fireman New York: Horace Waters,1855 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    Composed by Benjamin Jepson
  - The fire bells are ringing!: song & chorus New York: C. M. Cady,1877 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Homeless to-night Boston: White, Smith & Company,1873 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - The ship on fire!: a descriptive scena New York: Atwill,[1834 -1847] (Box 25, Folder 8)
    Words and Music by Henry Russell
    Written by Charles Mackey, Esq.
  - Fire fiend: a descriptive fantasie representing the buring of the Lindell Hotel [St. Louis, Mo.] St. Louis: Bollman & Schatzman,1867.Dayton: Fischer & Bro. ,1867 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    Composed by Henry Bollman
    Lithographer: Juls. Hutawa, Saint Louis
    Also published by G. Andre; & Co., Philadelphia.
  - Lindell grand march Cincinnati: A. C. Peters & Bro.,1853 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    Music by Carl Muller
    Lithographer: Ehrgott, Forbriger & Co., Lith., Cincinnati
  - Lindell Hotel schottisch St. Louis: Balmer & Weber,1863 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    Composed by August Waldauer
    Engraver J. Scharr, Eng.
- Series 16. Flowers
  - My pretty red rose New York: Frederick Blume,1877 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    Written and composed by Joseph P. Skelly
    Performed by D. S. Wambold
  - ÔTis the last rose of summer: the celebrated Irish air with an introduction and variations for the piano forte Boston: E. H. Wade,n.d. (Box 26, Folder 1)
    Music by Henri Herz
  - The last rose of summer: with an introduction and brilliant variations for the piano forte, as performed at all his concerts in the United States New York: Firth, Son & Co.,1848 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    Engraver Wakelam Engr., New York
  - The last rose of summer: morceau de salon [St. Louis]: Kunkel Brothers,1868.St. Louis: Mammoth Music House ,1868 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    Music by Charles Kunkel
  - Camelia polka Chicago: Root & Cady,n.d. (Box 26, Folder 1)
    Music by Edward Hoffman
    Lithographer: Chicago Lith. Company, Chicago
    From :Bridal Flowers for the Piano
  - My pretty red rose: ballad New York: Frederick Blume,1877 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    Words and Music by Joseph P. Skelly
  - ÔTis sweet to see the blooming rose: a song New York: James L. Hewitt & Co.,1843 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    Words by C. J. Jeffreys
    Lithographer: Thayer & Co., Lith., Boston
  - Leaf by leaf the roses fall Cincinnati: John Church & Co.,1865.Boston: O. Ditson & Co. ,1865 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    Composed by T. B. Bishop
    Words by Caroline Dana Howe
    Printer Wrightson & Co., Printers, Cincinnati
    Also published by Balmer & Weber, St. Louis; C. H. Ditson & Co., New York; Lee & Walker, Philadelphia; and Geo. F. Root & Sons, Chicago.
  - Leonora: romanza characteristique for soprano or tenor Boston: White-Smith Music Publishing Co.,1891 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Flowers! Bright flowers! Philadelphia: George Willig,1844.Lexington, KY: A. F. Skillman & Son ,1844 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    Music by J. E. Spilman
    Poetry by Miss. E. Scaife
  - The wandering Jew: grand valse brilliante Philadelphia: Lee & Walker,n.d. (Box 26, Folder 3)
    Music by F. Burgmuller
    From :The Flower Basket, a collection of new and elegant pieces for the piano by the best composers
  - The flora waltzes Boston: Wm. H. Oakes,1843.Boston: John Ashton & Co. ,1843 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    Composed by L. Schumann
  - Maiden's blush waltz New York: J. L. Peters,1866.Cincinnati: J. J. Dobermeyer & Co. ,1866 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    Lithographer: Ehrgott, Forbriger, & Co., Cincinnati
    Also published by De Motte Brothers, Chicago and J. J. Dobermeyer & Co., St. Louis.
  - Pink of perfection: valse caprice New York: J. L. Peters,1867 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    Music by Louis Wallis
  - Only a pansy blossom: waltz song Cincinnati: John Church & Co.,1882.Chicago: Root & Sons Music Co. ,1882 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    Music by Frank Howard
  - Pretty as a pink: fantasia with brilliant variations New York: J. L. Peters,1870.Saint Louis: J. J. Voellmecke ,1870 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    Also published by Dobmeyer & Newhall, Cincinnati; M. Gray, San Francisco and Portland; C. J. Whitney & Co., Detroit; and R. Morgan, Quebec.
  - Answer?: ballad for alto or baritone, with cornet obligato ad lib. Saint Louis: Balmer & Weber Music House Co.,1885 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    Composed by Alfred G. Robyn
- Series 17. Stephen Collins Foster First Editions
  - Willie, we have missed you New York: Firth, Pond & Co.,1854.Pittsburgh: H. Kleber ,1854 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    Written and composed by Stephen C. Foster
    From :Foster's Melodies
    Also published by Colburn & Field, Cincinnati; Wakeiam & Iucho, St. Louis; and P.P. Werlein, New Orleans.
  - Some folks New York: William A. Pond & Co.,1855.Pittsburgh: H. Kleber ,1855 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    From :Foster's Melodies No. 29
    Also published by W. F. Colburn, Cincinnati; W. W. Wakelam, St. Louis; and P.P. Werlein, New Orleans.
  - She was all the world to me New York: Horace Waters,1864.Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co. ,1864 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    Music by Stephen C. Foster
    Words by Dr. Duffy
  - My old Kentucky home, good night New York: Firth, Pond & Co.,1853.Pittsburgh: H. Kleber ,1853 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    From :Foster's Plantation Melodies No. 20
  - My loved one and my own, or, Eva: ballad New York: Firth, Pond & Co.,1858.Pittsburgh: H. Kleber ,1858 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    Engraver Green & Walker, Engraving, Boston
    From :Foster's Melodies No. 36
    Also published by G. Y. Fonda, Cincinnati and H. Pilcher & Sons, St. Louis.
  - Melinda May: the beautiful Ethiopian melody Baltimore: F. D. Benteen,1850.New Orleans: W. T. Mayo ,1850 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    Performed by New Orleans Serenaders
  - Massa's in de cold ground New York: Firth, Pond & Co.,1852.Baltimore: F. D. Benteen ,1852 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    Performed by Christy's Minstrels
    Also published by H. Kleber, Pittsburgh.
  - For the dear old flag I die! New York: Horace Waters,1862.Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co. ,1862 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    Poetry by George Cooper
    Printer Warren Music Stereotypers, New York
  - Hard times come again no more New York: Firth, Pond & Co.,1854.Pittsburgh: H. Kleber ,1854 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    Written and composed by Stephen Collins Foster
    Also published by Colburn & Field, Cincinnati; Faulds, Stone, & Morse, Louisville; W. W. Wakelam, St. Louis; P. P. Werlein, New Orleans.
  - Farewell my Lilly dear: a plantation melody New York: Firth, Pond & Co.,1851.Pittsburgh: H. Kleber ,1851 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Lula is gone: song New York: Firth, Pond & Co.,1858.Pittsburgh: H. Kleber & Bro. ,1858 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    Music by Stephen Collins Foster
    Poetry by Stephen Collins Foster
    From :Foster's Melodies, No. 33
- Series 18. L. M. Gottschalk
  - Le Mancenillier: sérénade Cleveland: S. Brainard & Co.,n.d. (Box 26, Folder 7)